Lakshika Saini

+91-7888918630 | lakshika.saini26@gmail.com | https://lakshikasaini.github.io | www.linkedin.com/in/lakshikasaini

PROFILE

Computer Science Engineer with 2 years of experience in data engineering and cloud solutions. I have a strong background in programming and skills in building scalable and efficient systems. I excel at solving complex technical problems and working with business stakeholders to ensure solutions meet strategic goals.

EDUCATION

Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology

Patiala, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

2019 - 2023

Graduated with 8.12 CGPA

SKILLS

Technical: C, C++, Python (OOPs, PySpark), Shell Scripting, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy), Flask, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ETL, Data Visualization, OpenPyXL

Tools: AWS (S3, Redshift, IAM, Glue, Cloud Formation, Cloud watch, Redshift, RDS), Tableau, Excel

EXPERIENCE

ZS Associates Gurgaon, India

Business Technology Solutions Associate

July 2023 – Present

- Automated manual tasks using Shell and Python scripting, improving operational efficiency.
- Delivered data engineering solutions with Python, SQL, and AWS services within Agile methodologies.
- Participated in requirements-gathering sessions with multiple business leaders to align technical solutions with business needs.
- Designed UI mock-ups, managed operations projects and authored key documentation (SOP, BRD, FSD, UAT Summary) to support project delivery.
- Mentored new associates, providing guidance on technical concepts and best practices.

Seneca Global IT Services Private Limited

Hyderabad, India

Python Developer

January 2023 – June 2023

- Developed a backend application for automating processes
- Streamlined data management and integration of interconnected excel sheets using python scripts with Flask and SQLAlchemy

PROJECTS

Data Engineering Full-Stack Data Product

- Built an end-to-end pipeline integrating multi-vendor data into AWS S3, processed via Glue workflows, and modelled in Redshift for Tableau dashboards and React.js portals.
- Automated ingestion and transformation using **Python, SQL, and AWS**, improving data reliability and enabling faster, insight-driven business decisions.

Flask-Tkinter Integration Application

• Refactored an existing **Tkinter desktop app** by decoupling business logic from UI, enabling integration with **Flask APIs** as a web backend, and designed UI mock-ups for seamless migration.

EXTRACURRICULARS

Unique World Record (2017) - Most Random digits memorized in one minute